MOHAMED EL FAKHARANY

2285 W Broadway, Anaheim, 92804, CA, USA, 1 (562) 382 5197, m_fakharany@yahoo.com

Summary

I'm certified sales professional with over 8 years experience and proven track record of achievement selling IT solutions to enterprise accounts. I consistently over achieved my sales quota, acquired new and developed existing accounts, built positive relationships and achieved customers satisfaction. I have strong communication and presentation skills and able to position a solution to all customer's levels.

I'm a Green Card holder.

Work Experience

Area Sales Manager / Ontario, CA

Oct 2014 - till now

NetXperts (Gold Cisco partner, System Integrator)

www.netxpets.com

- Managing Orange County and San Diego territory
- Growing relationships with key customers
- Prospecting new accounts in assigned area
- Sales presentations
- Negotiating solutions with partners and customers
- Coordinating internal teams to accomplish the work required to close the deals
- Developing partnerships with vendors AM
- Participating in vendors product training

Senior Account Manager / Cairo, Egypt Jul 2013-Sep 2014

BMB Group (Gold Cisco Partner, Systems Integrator, EMC, Palo Alto, McAfee, Vmware, Riverbed partner)

http://www.bmbgroup.com

- Handling Fortune 100 accounts (Kraft, Nestle, Mars, Danone, Nissan etc)
- Managing and growing local and international markets (Egypt, Lybya)
- Establishing and maintaining relationships with new and existing customers
- Working with Channel Partners
- Coordinating internal teams to accomplish the work required to close the deals
- Developing and managing a sales pipeline
- Monthly forecast/weekly reports

Sales Account Manager / Cairo, Egypt

Nov 2011-Jul 2013 <u>BMB Group</u> Systems Integrator, Gold Cisco Partner, EMC, Palo Alto, McAfee, Vmware, Riverbed partner)

http://www.bmbgroup.com

- Identifying and validating new opportunities across the assigned sector
- Preparing cost sheet and quotation for every project
- Developing and managing a sales pipeline
- Monthly forecast/weekly reports

Senior Sales Executive / Cairo, Egypt Apr 2009-Nov 2011

Etisalat ISP

http://www.etisalat.com

- Exploring business growth opportunities with current and potential Key Enterprise Customers
- Maintaining relationships between Customers and Etisalat ISP
- Preparing Sales offer and following up till close the deal
- Coordinating between Customers and internal presales, project managers and technical team regarding customers' requirements
- Delivering sales presentations to high-level management
- Managing the work of account executives
- Monthly forecast/weekly reports
- IT knowledge (VPN, Internet, Cisco routers, 3G, Microwave)

Sales Executive / Cairo, Egypt Jan 2008-Mar 2009

Al Amin Technological Systems (Office and banking equipments)

http://www.alamintech.com/

- Meeting and exceeding sales targets
- Generating new business and developing business relationship with existing customers
- Forecasting and reporting

Telesales Executive / Cairo, Egypt Jan 2007-Dec 2007

Ecco Outsourcing

http://www.eccooutsourcing.com/company.html

- Meeting and exceeding sales targets
- Communicating with potential clients (residents in USA) by phone to sell long distance phone cards

Education	The Future Academy (Cairo, Egypt), May 2007
Education	
	Degree - Bachelor Major - Information System
	- Wajor - Information System
Languages	
~	English (Fluent), Arabic (Native)
Computer and	MS Office, Windows Vista, XP, 7
Personal Skills	• Oracle, CRM, OMS, NTS (Excellent)
	 Hard worker, goal, and results oriented attitude
	• Excellent communication skills, strong leadership, problem solving, decision
	making, and team building skills
Courses and	• Veeam Sales Professional 2015 (Certificate)
Certificates obtain	1 /
	• Riverbad Sales Associate 2014 (Certificate)
	• Sales Enablement in Security Cisco 2014
	 Selling Cisco Data Center Architectures Course 2013
	 Palo Alto Sales Course 2013
	• Unlimited Selling Success Course 2012 (Certificate)
	• EMC Course 2012
	BMB Best Sales Achiever Q4 2012 (Certificate)
	• Etisalat ISP Best Achiever 2010 (Certificate)
	Apple&Orange Finance 2011 Course (Certificate)
	• SPIN Selling Course 2010